Mss.Ms.Coll.109
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence, 25.25 linear feet
  - Veterans Administration, 1946-50; 40 items (Box 49)
  - Victor, George, 1985; 4 items (Box 49)
  - Victory, Dick, 1966; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Viseltear, Elaine, 1984; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Voegelin, Anna M, 1942; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Voegelin, C.F, 1950; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Vogelsang, Roger, 1972; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Vogt, William, 1960; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Voigt, Neil, 1985; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Von Bertalanffy, L, 1955; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Von Bonin, Gerhardt, 1946-1954; 16 items (Box 49)
  - Von Foerster, Heinz, 1964; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Von Koenigswald, G.H.R, 1965; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Vondracek, V, undated; 1 item (Box 49)
  - Vos, Johanna K, 1982-1994; undated; 13 items (Box 49)
  - Vuturo, Anthony, 1989; 2 items (Box 49)
  - V-Misc, 1972-1996; 8 items (Box 49)
  - Wade, James O, 1981; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wade, Lili L, 1989; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wadelton, Cathy, 1972; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wadler, S. Leonard, 1950; 1975; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Wadsworth, James J, 1962; 6 items (Box 50)
  - Waggoner, Colleen, 1989; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wagner, Charles A, 1978; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wagner, Durrett, 1968; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Walch, Mark, 1986; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Walck, Henry Z, 1952; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wald, George, 1968; 1969; 3 items (Box 50)
  - Waldman, Bernard, 1967; 1980; undated; 3 items (Box 50)
  - Waldman, Marcella, 1981-1994; undated; 9 items (Box 50)
  - Waldron, Adele, 1981; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Waldron, T.F, 1982; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Walker, Alan (Program Corp. of America), 1977; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Walker, Alan (Harvard University), 1976; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Wall, Graydon, 1997; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wallace, H.A, 1955; 3 items (Box 50)
  - Wallace, Irving, 1965-1976; 13 items (Box 50)
  - Wallace, Mike, 1957; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wallin, Julie, 1982; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wallis, Wilson D, 1940-1958; 4 items (Box 50)
  - Walsh, Joan Logue, 1979; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Walter, H.E, 1940; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Walton, Andra, 1982; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Walton, Clarence C, 1966; 1969; 3 items (Box 50)
  - Waltzer, H.E, 1956; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Warburg, James P, 1968; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Ward, Peter, 1952; 1970; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Waring, Mary Matthew, 1956; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Warndof, Fiona, 1986; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Warner, Regena, 1981; 1982; 3 items (Box 50)
  - Warner, Samuel J, 1957-1980; 4 items (Box 50)
  - Warner, W. Lloyd, 1937; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Warren, Hamilton, 1949; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Warren, Henry V, 1960; 3 items (Box 50)
  - Warren, I. David, 1972; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Warren, Peter, 1979; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Warren, V, 1994; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Washburn, Sherwood L, 1949-1981; 6 items (Box 50)
    First name established through confirmation of nickname (Sherry), as well as the origin of the item. Washburn, an anthropologist, had retired after teaching at the University of California, Berkeley until his retirement in 1979.
  - Watson, David, 1941; 1961; 4 items (Box 50)
  - Watson, Joy, 1987; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Watterson, Henry, 1898; 1 item (Box 50)
    Letter from Henry Watterson, Editor of the Louisville Courier-Journal to the Hon. W.B. Allison, Senator from Iowa.
  - Wattie, Margaret, 1937; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Watts, Maria B, 1989; 1991; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Watts, Olivia Harvard, 1971; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wayne, Helena, 1978; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weary, Gerald, 1953; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weatherhead, A. Dixon MD, 1965; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weatherly, Gerald, 1977; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Webb, Alan, 1987; 1993; undated; 3 items (Box 50)
  - Webb, Anne, 1994; 4 items (Box 50)
  - Webb, Jon, undated; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Webber, Howard R, 1970; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wechsler, James A, April 10; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wecter, Dixon, 1948; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wedge, Bryant, 1967; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weglyn, Michi, 1977; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weidenreich, Franz, 1946; 1947; 5 items (Box 50)
  - Weille, F. Blair, 1971; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weinberg, Marvin MD, 1954; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weinberger, Andrew P, 1962; 1963; 4 items (Box 50)
  - Weingartner, Charles, 1967; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weininger, Otto, 1984; 1986; 6 items (Box 50)
  - Weintroub, Benjamin, 1943; 1950; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Weiss, Charles, 1976; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Weiss, Ira P, 1975; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weissberger, L. Arnold, 1980; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weissman, Inez, 1978; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weitz, Shirley, 1977; 1978; 7 items (Box 50)
  - Welch, Martha G, 1984-1992; undated; 15 items (Box 50)
  - Welke, Robert J, 1977; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wellck, Rene, 1988; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Wendt, Gerald, 1952-1967; 5 items (Box 50)
  - Wentworth, Richard L, 1965; 1966; 4 items (Box 50)
  - Werkmeister, Lucyle, 1963; 1969; 4 items (Box 50)
  - Werner, Bernard, 1938-1941; undated; 3 items (Box 50)
  - Wertz, Dorothy C, 1978; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Wes, 1965; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wescott, Roger W, 1963-1990; 4 items (Box 50)
  - West, Mary, 1971; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Westlake, Neda M, 1965; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Weybright, Victor, 1958; 1965; 2 items (Box 50)
  - Weymouth, F.W, 1943; 1 item (Box 50)
  - Wheeler, Harvey, 1983; 3 items (Box 51)
  - Wheeler, Stephan, 1930-1935; undated; 9 items (Box 51)
  - Wherry, Margaret, 1954; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Whistler, Lawrence, 1958; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Whitaker, Ramona Pando, 1993; 2 items (Box 51)
  - White, Burton L, 1982; 2 items (Box 51)
  - White, D.F, 1939; 1 item (Box 51)
  - White, George Abbott, 1966; 1 item (Box 51)
  - White, Hedy, 1977; 1 item (Box 51)
  - White, Leslie A, 1959; 1964; 1965; 6 items (Box 51)
  - White, Lillian G. Hansen, 1971; 1 item (Box 51)
  - White, Mary, 1983; 6 items (Box 51)
  - White, Mary Beth, 1979; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Whitelaw, Graeme, 1968; 2 items (Box 51)
  - Whitfield, Grace, 1980; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Whiting, Roland, 1969; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Whitmoyer, Debra, 1982; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Whitmyre, Linda, 1981; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Whittlestone, Walter G. (Wattie), 1977-1986; 4 items (Box 51)
  - Wholey, Dennis, November 18; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Whyte, L.L., 1964; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wieck, Fred D., 1958; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wiener, Alexander S, 1943-1967; undated; 51 items (Box 50)
  - Wiggins, Henry H, 1950; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wilke, Martha, 1977; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Williams, Dell, 1978; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Williams, Jean L, 1972; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Williams, Kelli, 1996; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Williams, Lucy, 1968; 2 items (Box 51)
  - Williams, Roger J, 1967; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Williams, Silvia, 1980; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Williams, Thomas R, 1970; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Williamson, John, 1986; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Williamson, Mark and Charlotte, 1984; 1988; undated; 8 items (Box 51)
  - Willis, R.A, 1959; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wilner, Charles, 1943; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wilson, Charles, 1958; 1977; 2 items (Box 51)
  - Wilson, Douglas, 1989; 2 items (Box 51)
  - Wilson, Edward O, 1973; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wilson, Edwin B, 1941; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wilson, J. Kent, 1982; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wilson, Toni Annette, 1990; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Winchester, A.M, 1959; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Windle, Edith, 1936; 1937; 2 items (Box 51)
  - Winkler, Henry, 1981; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Winslade, William J, 1983; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Winston, Ellen B, 1981; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Winton, F.R, 1932; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wismer, Perey, 1947; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wittenberg, Philip, 1964; 1965; 5 items (Box 51)
  - Wittlin, Alma S, 1977; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wittmer, Felix, 1968; 1970; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wogan, Robert, 1965; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wolf, Elliot R, 1976; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wolfe, Barbara Alice, 1945; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wolfe, Don M, 1969; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wolff, Harold G. MD, 1960; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wolff, Helen, 1967; 3 items (Box 51)
  - Wolff, Kurt, 1946; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wolfson, H.A, 1946; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wolman, Benjamin B, undated; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Women's International Network, 1979; 1980; 2 items (Box 51)
  - Woodbridge, Richard C, 1998; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Woodburne, Russell T, 1968; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Woodriff, J.R. Piers, 1978; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Woodward, C. Vann, 1971; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Woollard, 1939; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Worden, Shelley, 1989; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wormington, H.M, 1947; 1964; 2 items (Box 51)
  - Wright, Barbara Ayn, 1989; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wright, Benjamin F, 1953; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wright, E.N, 1969; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wylie, Anne Stiles, undated; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wyly, Lawrence T, 1969-1978; 3 items (Box 51)
  - Wyman, L.C, 1946; 1 item (Box 51)
  - Wynne-Tyson, Jon, 1977-1994; undated; 40 items (Box 51)
  - W-Misc, 1943-1997; 19 items (Box 51)
  - Yacasua, L.T, 1975; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Yanoff, Jerome C, 1982; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Yaworsky, Arlene, 1989; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Yee, Albert, 1983; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Yee, Ying K, 1983; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Yengoyan, Aram A, 1979; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Yerkes, Robert M, 1943; 1953; 4 items (Box 52)
  - Yesavage, Diane Lapp, 1993; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Yinger, J. Milton, 1985; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Young, Genevieve, 1972; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Young, J.Z, 1962; 1972; 2 items (Box 52)
  - Young, Kimball, 1945; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Ysais, Andrea, 1979; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Yudewitz, Hyman, 1982; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Zacharias, Leona, 1978; 1979; 3 items (Box 52)
  - Zaniello, Tom, 1984; 1987; 2 items (Box 52)
  - Zaslawski, Ivy, 1973; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Zawadsky, Bo, 1981; 2 items (Box 52)
  - Zawilenski, Larry, 1971; undated; 4 items (Box 52)
  - Zeisberg, Millard, 1979; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Zeitlin & VerBruge Booksellers, 1941-1989; 31 items (Box 52)
  - Zeuner, Frederick E, 1948; 1950; 4 items (Box 52)
  - Zevin, Ben D, 1956; 2 items (Box 52)
  - Zilborg, Gergory MD, 1951; 1953; 2 items (Box 52)
  - Zimmer, Dick, 1991; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Zimmerman, Ivan, 1979; 1 item (Box 52)
  - Zirkle, Conway, 1939-1959; 5 items (Box 52)
  - Zuckerman, Solly, Sir, 1934-1968; 12 items (Box 52)
  - Z-Misc, 1972;1977; 1989; undated; 4 items (Box 52)
  - Unidentified, 1933-1998; 92 items (Box 52)
- Correspondence with Publishers, 3.5 linear feet
  Series II is comprised of Montagu’s correspondence with the many publishers he worked with in over 50 years of writing. The chief correspondent is Oxford University Press, publisher of Man and Aggression and Race and IQ.
  - Abelard-Schuman, Correspondence, 1950-1970; undated; 220 items (Box 53)
  - Abelard-Schuman, Royalty Statements, 1953-1961; 31 items (Box 53)
  - Abelard-Schuman, Legal Documents, 1949-1962; 5 items (Box 53)
  - Acadian House Publishing, 1983-1997; 40 items (Box 53)
  - American Book Company, 1964-1967; 6 items (Box 53)
  - Aretê Publishing, Correspondence, 1978-1980; 37 items (Box 53)
  - Aretê Publishing, Undated notes, 8 items (Box 53)
  - Aretê Publishing, Travel Itineraries, 1979; 18 items (Box 53)
  - Barnes and Noble, 1954; 1983-1985; undated; 6 items (Box 53)
  - Beltz, 1971; 1972; 6 items (Box 53)
  - Bury Free Press, undated; 5 items (Box 53)
  - Columbia University Press, Correspondence, 1943-1988; 12 items (Box 53)
  - Columbia Univserity Press, Publishing Agreements, 1942-1976; 5 items (Box 53)
  - Contracts and Copyrights, 1952-1982; undated; 38 items (Box 53)
  - Copyrights, 1955-1985; undated; 11 items (Box 53)
  - David R. Godine, Publisher, Inc, 1975-1993; undated; 38 items (Box 53)
  - Dial, The, 1980; 8 items (Box 53)
  - Doubleday Publishing, 1941-1971; undated; 24 items (Box 53)
  - Dutton, Inc., 1969-1984; undated; 69 items (Box 53)
  - Farrar, Straus and Giroux, Inc, 1971; 2 items (Box 53)
  - Free Press, 1967-1975; 22 items (Box 53)
  - Grolier Incorporated, Correspondence, 1953-1998; undated; 57 items (Box 53)
  - Grolier Incorporated, Contracts, 1983-1998; 15 items (Box 53)
  - Grove Press, 1967-1988; 7 items (Box 54)
  - Harper Collins, Correspondence, 1951-1996; 159 items (Box 54)
  - Harper Collins, Financial Statements, 1955-1986; 15 items (Box 54)
  - Harper Collins, Publishing Agreements, 1952-1984; 6 items (Box 54)
  - Harper Collins, Royalty Statements 1990s, 1990-1995; 13 items (Box 54)
  - Harper Collins, Royalty Statements 1980s, 1980-1989; 92 items (Box 54)
  - Harper Collins, Royalty Statements 1970s, 1970-1979; 90 items (Box 54)
  - Harper Collins, Royalty Statements 1952-1969, 41 items (Box 54)
  - Hawthorn Books, Correspondence, 1965-1979; 150 items (Box 55)
  - Hawthorn Books, Undated Correspondence, 21 items (Box 55)
  - Hawthorn Books, Publishing Agreements, 1965-1969; undated; 8 items (Box 55)
  - Hawthorn Books, Rotalty Statements, 1966-1978; 125 items (Box 55)
  - Helstar S.A, 1973; 1974; 18 items (Box 55)
  - Laurence Pollinger Limited, 1969-1981; 21 items (Box 55)
  - Literary Agents, 1969-1971; 21 items (Box 55)
  - McGraw Hill, 1976-1987; 7 items (Box 55)
  - Macmillan Co., Correspondence, 1965-1995; 52 items (Box 55)
  - Macmillan Co., Publishing Agreements, 1952-1972; undated; 9 items (Box 55)
  - Macmillan Co., Royalty Statements, 1990-1992; 5 items (Box 55)
  - Meiji Tosho, Ltd, 1969; 8 items (Box 55)
  - Mitchell Beazley Ltd, 1973; 1974; 14 items (Box 55)
  - Miscellaneous A-C, 1944-1989; 118 items (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous D-F, 1953-1990; 51 items (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous G-I, 1937-1988; 59 items (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous J-L, 1953-1993; 76 items (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous M-P, 1944-1995; undated; 95 items (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous Q-T, 1954-1990; undated; 70 items (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous, U-Z, 1956-1991; undated; 74 items (Box 56)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified, undated; 19 items (Box 56)
  - New American Library of World Literature, 1962; 1 item (Box 57)
  - Oxford University Press, Correspondence, 1976-1995, 83 items (Box 57)
  - Oxford University Press, Correspondence, 1972-1975, 150 items (Box 57)
  - Oxford University Press, Correspondence, 1951-1971, 216 items (Box 57)
  - Oxford University Press, Correspondence, unattributed, undated, 125 items (Box 57)
  - Oxford University Press, Publishing Agreements, 1960-1981; 14 items (Box 57)
  - Oxford University Press, Royalty Statements, 1962-1983; 42 items (Box 57)
  - Porter Sargent, Correspondence, 1955-1985; 5 items (Box 58)
  - Porter Sargent, Publishing Agreements, 1955; 1956; 2 items (Box 58)
  - Prentice Hall, 1974; 1982; undated; 3 items (Box 58)
  - Psychology Today, 1968; 1980; undated; 11 items (Box 58)
  - Putnam, Correspondence, 1959-1984; 94 items (Box 58)
  - Putnam, Publishing Agreements, 1959-1969; 5 items (Box 58)
  - Putnam, Royalty Statements, 1967-1984; 40 items (Box 58)
  - Quadrangle Books, 1970-1977; 32 items (Box 58)
  - Random House, 1953; undated; 2 items (Box 58)
  - Redbook Magazine, 1965-1967; 7 items (Box 58)
  - Sage Publications, 1988-1995; 46 items (Box 58)
  - Saturday Review, 1963-1973; 15 items (Box 58)
  - Science Digest, 1980-1985; 47 items (Box 58)
  - Science Research Associates, Correspondence, 1952-1976; 96 items (Box 58)
  - Science Research Associates, Misc. Correspondence, undated, 17 items (Box 58)
  - Science Research Associates, Ethics statement, undated; 1 item (Box 58)
  - Science Research Associates, Modern Man, manuscript, undated; 1 item (Box 58)
  - Science Research Associates, Royalty Statements, 1953-1972; 45 items (Box 58)
  - The Sciences, 1977-1983; 27 items (Box 58)
  - Schuman, undated; 18 items (Box 58)
  - Seibido Publishing, Correspondence, 1970-1988; 38 items (Box 58)
  - Seibido Publishing, Royalty Statements, 1971-1986; 31 items (Box 58)
  - Sexology Magazine, 1962-1972; 31 items (Box 58)
  - Simon and Schuster, 1964-1989; 16 items (Box 58)
  - Sound Seminars, 1953-1964; undated; 18 items (Box 58)
  - Think Magazine, 1960-1967; 9 items (Box 58)
  - Time Magazine, 1942; 1967; 2 items (Box 58)
  - University of Arizona Press, Correspondence, 1984-1986; 42 items (Box 59)
  - University of Arizona Press, Miscellaneous, unattributed correspondence, undated; 22 items (Box 59)
  - University of California Press, 1969-1995; 43 items (Box 59)
  - University of Hawaii at Manoa, 1992-1994; 10 items (Box 59)
  - U.S. News and World Report, 1981; 1982; 14 items (Box 59)
  - Van Nostrand, Correspondence, 1961-1976; 30 items (Box 59)
  - Van Nostrand, Royalty Statements, 1962-1975; 15 items (Box 59)
  - Vista, 1966-1971; 20 items (Box 59)
  - World and I, The, 1989-1990; 11 items (Box 59)
  - World Publishing Co., Correspondence, 1966-1974, 54 items (Box 59)
  - World Publishing Co., Correspondence, 1963-1965, 100 items (Box 59)
  - World Publishing Co., Correspondence, 1959-1962, 65 items (Box 59)
  - World Publishing Co., Correspondence, 1956-1958, 85 items (Box 59)
  - World Publishing Co., Miscellaneous unattributed correspondence, undated; 45 items (Box 59)
  - World Publishing Co., Publishing Agreements, 1963; 1969; 2 items (Box 59)
  - World Publishing Co., Copyrights, 1961-1965; 3 items (Box 59)
  - World Publishing Co., Royalty Statements, 1958-1973; 150 items (Box 59)
- Works By, 12.75 linear feet
  Series III consists of works by Ashley Montagu, related notes, and correspondence; reviews of individual works are also included. It contains complete book manuscripts, as well as journal and popular magazine articles. Much of the series is comprised of undated manuscripts of both published and unpublished articles, typewritten by Montagu. Also included are class notes taken by Montagu during his time as a graduate student at Columbia University from classes taught by Ruth Benedict and Franz Boas, as well as course materials from classes he taught at Harvard. Book reviews written by Montagu are included, as well as works by other authors that were included in works edited by Montagu. Unpublished poems authored by Montagu are also included, which highlight the diversity of his interests and abilities.
  - "26. Love can deny nothing to love...," Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Abominable Showman, The, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Abortion, Correspondence, 1967; undated; 5 items (Box 60)
  - About Adam and Eve, Foreword, Correspondence, 1971-1998; 7 items (Box 60)
  - About Adam and Eve, Foreword, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The Adaptive Value of Labor Pains, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The Adaptive Value of Labor Pains, Review, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Adaptive Value of Labor Pains: II, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Addiction, Correspondence, 1965-1973; 3 items (Box 60)
  - Adolescence, Correspondence, 1966; undated; 2 items (Box 60)
  - Adolescent's Unreadiness for Pregnancy and Motherhood, Draft, 1981; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Adoption, Notes, undated; 2 items (Box 60)
  - Adoption, Draft, 1980; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Adoption: Reflecting America?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - African Origins of the American Negro, Notes, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - African Origins of the American Negro, Drafts, undated; 3 items (Box 60)
  - Aggression and the Evolution of Man, Draft, 1974; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Aggressive Words, Notes, undated; 38 items (Box 60)
  - Aging, Notes, undated; 2 items (Box 60)
  - Aging of Humanity, The, Draft, 1967; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Aldous Huxley: Brave New World, Draft, 1972; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Alfred Adler and Social Interest, Correspondence, 1969; 1970; 16 items (Box 60)
  - Alfred Adler and Social Interest, Drafts, undated; 3 items (Box 60)
  - The American Car, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The American Family and American Character, Draft, 1961; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The American Indian: The First Victim, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The American Male, Notes, undated; 4 items (Box 60)
  - The American Male, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The American Way of Life, Review, 1967; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The American Woman, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - An Analysis of Impressionism, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anatomy, Notes, undated; 47 items (Box 60)
  - Anatomy, Correspondence, 1937-1981; 3 items (Box 60)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Notes, undated; 100 items (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Correspondence, 1942-1975; 18 items (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Chapters 8 and 10, Partial Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Ms Draft, Ch. 1-4, undated; 1 item (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Ms Draft, Ch. 5-8, undated; 1 item (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Ms Draft, Ch. 9-12, undated; 1 item (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Ms Draft, Ch. 13-16, undated; 1 item (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Partial Draft, 1941; 1 item (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Reviews, 1967-1974; 61 items (Box 60a)
  - The Anatomy of Swearing, Ephemera, undated; 2 items (Box 60a)
  - The Ancestry of Man, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 60)
  - The Ancient Greeks Do Not Recognize Race, Partial Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anita Hill, Notes, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The Annihilation of Privacy, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The Anterior Nasal Spine in Man, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - An Anthropologist Looks at Circumcision and its Probable Origin, Abstract, 1991; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology and Genetics, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology and Medical Education, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology and Medicine, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology and Social Engineering, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology and World History, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology at Columbia Sixty Years Ago, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology Coments, Notes, undated; 60 items (Box 60)
  - Anthropology Comments, Correspondence, 1942-1950; 26 items (Box 60)
  - The Anthropology of Peace and Nonviolence, Notes, undated; 2 items (Box 60)
  - The Anthropology of Peace and Nonviolence, Foreword, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology, Religion and Racism, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - Anthropology Today, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 60)
  - The Antiquity of Homo Sapiens, Correspondence, 1946; 1 item (Box 61)
    Includes a minorly marked up copy of the draft of the same title, marked up by Gerhardt von Bonin.
  - The Antiquity of Homo Sapiens, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Anxiety and Society, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Anxiety as an Individual and Social Symptom, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Are American and English the Same Language?, Draft, 1962; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Are We Forgetting How to Eat?, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Art, Curriculum, And Culture, Draft, 1954; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Ashley Montagu on Nasion, Menton, Notes, undated; 7 items (Box 61)
  - Ashley Montagu on Nasion, Menton, Correspondence, 1934; 1938; 2 items (Box 61)
  - Ashley Montagu on Nasion, Menton, Draft, 1938; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Ashley Montagu on Robert Frost, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - "At the turn of the twentieth century...," Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Australia, Notes, undated; 5 items (Box 61)
  - Autism, Notes, undated; 4 items (Box 61)
  - Austism, Correspondence, 1973-1986; 6 items (Box 61)
  - Baby Lambskins, Notes, 1978; 1983; undated; 6 items (Box 61)
  - Baby Labskins, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Backs and Backache, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - "Barriers of communication no longer exist between peoples," Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Beauty, Notes, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Behavior, Correspondence, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Belief in Action, Draft, 1984; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Bibliography, 1936-1949; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Birth Rites, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Bloody: The Natural History of a Word, Draft, undated; 1 item (Box 61)
  - Blushing, Notes, undated; 4 items (Box 61)
  - The Bomb, Drafts, undated; 2 items (Box 61)
  - Bones, Notes, undated; 2 items (Box 61)
  - Bones, Correspondence, 1954-1956; 3 items (Box 61)
  - The Book of Baby Massage, Introduction, Correspondence, 1988; 2 items (Box 61)
  - The Book of Baby Massage, Introduction, Draft, 1988; 1 item (Box 61)